# Application Developer | Software Project Management

Innovative and diversified Software Application Developer, with a solid history of design and development expertise. Talent for identifying, isolating and resolving coding issues and analyzing end-user needs to align capabilities with overall objectives. Regarded as an innovator, developing software solutions for high-growth organizations like Sony, Pandora, and MLB, and creating a stronger posture within competitive markets.

- Software Development
- JavaScript, ¡Query, HTML, CSS, Qt QML, XML
- Quality Assurance & Testing
- Object Oriented Programming Full Life Cycle Project Mgmt
- Client Relationship Mgmt
- Agile Methodologies
- JIRA/HEAT Help Desk

## Career Experience

### **D-LINK SYSTEMS INC.**, Fountain Valley, CA

Demonstrated exceptional finesse working autonomously, driving production of robust software solutions, managing the technical-end of multiple set-top boxes and developed and maintained code utilizing JavaScript, Qt, Python and **XML** 

#### SENIOR APPLICATION DEVELOPER - REMOTE (2013 – 2017)

- Led technical support operations, designed application UI mockups and assets, utilizing Photoshop. Modified code, resolving errors and to control potentially negative impacts to the production lifecycle.
- Nurtured partnerships with 3<sup>rd</sup> party developers to facilitate the development and launch of set-top applications.

#### **BOXEE INC.**. New York, NY

Content manager & lead application developer of native and intuitive set-top applications. Developed PHP web crawlers to aggregate movie and TV data, enabling the design of a more intuitive set-top box.

## **APPLICATION DEVELOPER - REMOTE** (2009 – 2013)

- Worked collaboratively with industry moguls like Sony, MLB, NHL, TED, and Pandora, to pioneer proprietary software solutions that launched them into leading roles within a highly competitive market.
- Developed application API's, maintaining the API documentation, and created internal web application to validate content XML documents, from partners, integrating video, etc., into the platform.
- Developed and maintained playback control scripts integrating set top box remote to video playback in internal browser utilizing JavaScript.

### TD BANK NA, Mount Laurel, NJ

Worked both in a team setting & autonomously, as the on-call agent, providing multi-tiered troubleshooting. Effectively enhanced resolution times, and managed queries at various threat levels.

## IT SERVICE DESK | LEVEL 2 REPRESENTATIVE (2007 - 2009)

Created a comprehensive knowledge-base, ensuring high levels of proficiency. Consistently updated information and delivered employee training. Redesigned help desk logo using Inkscape vector software.

## **Education & Credentials**

Associate of Applied Science in Computer Information Systems, Camden County College, Blackwood, NJ Professional Development Training: Oracle PL/SQL & Oracle DBA Certificate, DBA University Online

Technical Knowledge: JavaScript, iQuery, HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, React, Qt QML, Python, PHP, Bash, SQL, PL/SQL, RESTful API, SOAP, HTTP Live Streaming, OOP, RDBMS, Ajax, JSON, RSS/ATOM, GIT, Node.js, NPM, Gulp, Bower, Photoshop, Illustrator, Inkscape, GIMP, OSX, Linux, Windows